<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<conversations>
	
<!--Pet dialogue-->
	
	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Hyrkhound Pet">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			{{emote|*Jerenah =verb:turn= in circles before lying down.*}}~
			{{emote|*Jerenah =verb:chase= =pronouns.possessive= tail.*}}~
			{{emote|*Jerenah =verb:lap= some drool right back up.*}}~
			{{emote|*Jerenah =verb:get= up on =pronouns.possessive= hind legs.*}}
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Live and drool, friendly hyrkhound.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>
	
	
	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Brainkitty Pet">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			Kids these days have it easy: when I was young, glotrot used to spoil your whole water supply.~
			Back in my days, people knew the difference between daggers and short swords.~
			Young'uns today complicate everything... The Moon what now? They're called the Deathlands, darn it!~
			Ambidextry everywhere... Way back when, this used to really mean something.~
			Humph. Who are you again?~
			{{emote|*Alther =verb:concentrate= intensely for a few seconds.*}}
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, elderly feline.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>
  

<!--Important NPCs-->


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Warden Arendurath">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm a tree.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">You're a tree.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Catgod">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm a cat god.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">True.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Doggod">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm a dog god.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Very true.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_DogMayor">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm a dog mayor.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Very true.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_CatMayor">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm a cat mayor.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Very true.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_DogLover">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm in love with a cat.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Cute.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>

	
	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_CatLover">
		
		<node ID="Start">
		  <text>
			I'm in love with a dog.
		  </text>
		  <choice GotoID="End">Scandalous.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>	


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_DogChef">
		
		<node ID="Start" IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="3">
			<text>			
				{{emote|*The heads argue and bicker among each other in impenetrable cacophony.*}}		
			</text>
			<choice ID="Trade" Load="Remove" />
			<choice GotoID="End">{{emote|*back away slowly*}}</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Start" IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="3">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{emote|*The first head turns towards you, and greets you apathetically.*}}

				Welcome to Growarow's Preserved Goods... Need any food for the road?

				{{emote|*The second head echoes that greeting.*}}

				{{Y|And you came to Growarow's Trading Emporium... Can we interest you in some of our fine goods, friend?}}
				
				{{emote|*The third head chimes in.*}}

				{{K|Preserved! Emporium!}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{emote|*The first head turns towards you, and greets you energetically.*}}

				Welcome to Growarow's Preserved Goods! Need any food for the road?

				{{emote|*The second head echoes that greeting.*}}

				{{Y|And glad you came to Growarow's Trading Emporium! Can we interest you in some of our fine goods, friend?}}		
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Work" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_ChefQuest">I am looking for work. Do you require assistance with anything?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="TarBones" IfHaveActiveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_ChefQuest" IfHaveItem="TarBones">I have found the secret ingredient you were looking for.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Division" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">What is happening with the other village?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Opinion" IfHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1" IfNotFinishedQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest3" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1~Brief">What are your stances on the division between Shik and Spar?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="TwoHeads">I was not expecting that amount of heads.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="About">What do you do in Shik?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, all of you.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Work">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Bones! Bones!}}

				{{emote|*The second head stays silent as the first head chimes in.*}}

				More than ever. Pray tell, are you much of a cook?
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{Y|We do not, but we are certain Growarow does, friend.}}	

				{{emote|*The first head chimes in.*}}
				
				That we do. Pray tell, are you much of a cook?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="CookALot">
				<text>My skill is recognized far and wide, and I know a fellow chef when I see one. What are you preparing? Freeze-dried yuckwheat? Fermented tortoise scute? Hoarshroom jam?</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_RequirePart" Part="CookingAndGathering_CarbideChef " Render="Cooking and Gathering: Carbide Chef" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="CookABit">
				<text>I am enough of a cook to follow recipes, at least. Do you need me to retrieve some?</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_RequirePart" Part="CookingAndGathering" Render="Cooking and Gathering: Meal Preparation" />
			</choice>		
			<choice GotoID="DoNotCook">I can improvise with foraged ingredients -- enough to keep myself fed, at least.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I will come back to you on that matter.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="CookALot">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Bones! Bones!}}

				{{emote|*The second head tries to keep the third one silent, to no avail.*}}

				We cannot reveal it before it is done, and we are lacking a certain ingredient. Could you maybe fetch it for us?
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				We cannot reveal it before it is done! We are sure you understand. Although we are lacking a certain ingredient. Would you care to obtain it for us?
				
				{{emote|*The second head stays silent.*}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief1">Anything for another student of the culinary arts. What do you need?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Maybe later. For now, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="CookABit">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Bones! Bones!}}

				{{emote|*The second head tries to keep the third one silent, to no avail.*}}

				The recipe we already have. It is our secret ingredient we are lacking -- could you fetch it for us?
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{Y|You do not lack initiative, friend!}}	
		
				Nothing that complicated. But we are missing our secret ingredient. Would you care to obtain it for us?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief1">A secret ingredient? Please tell me more.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Maybe later. For now, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>
		
		<node ID="DoNotCook">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Bones! Bones!}}

				{{emote|*The second head tries to keep the third one silent, to no avail.*}}

				We will keep things simple then. We are missing the key ingredient to our specialty dish -- could you fetch it for us?
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{Y|There is beauty in simplicity, friend.}}	
		
				There certainly is. To keep matters simple, we are missing the key ingredient to our specialty dish. Would you care to obtain it for us?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief1">This sounds important, please tell me more.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Maybe later. For now, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>











		<node ID="Brief1">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				text
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				text
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_ChefQuest">will do</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">wont do</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="TarBones">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				text
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				text
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Reward">more</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">libndink</choice>	
		</node>
		
		<node ID="Reward" AllowEscape="false">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				text
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				text
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">thx</choice>	
		</node>














		<node ID="Division" AllowEscape="false">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{emote|*The second head does not have time to answer before being cut off.*}} 
				
				{{K|Tree! Gun!}}

				... We have our paws full here. If you are looking into this matter, you should confer with Warden Arendubark. He can be found in the northern outskirts.
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{emote|*The first head prepares to answer, but reconsiders.*}} 
				
				{{Y|There is not much that we can say, friend. Fetch Warden Arendubark, north of the wall -- he has been trying to fix this matter for many moons, now.}}		
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">I will talk to the warden, then. In the meantime, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="Opinion">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Cat! Friend!}}

				{{emote|*None of the larger heads contradict this exclamation.*}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{emote|*Mild annoyance flashes on both their faces.*}}

				{{Y|It is all quite ridiculous, friend.}}
				
				Can you picture what succulent meal we could prepare with a new tinker-touched oven? We fail to see how this helps either Shik or Spar.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">I see. Can I ask you something else?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">A concise answer. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="TwoHeads">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				Neither were we. Please ignore our new partner...

				{{Y|As Growarow says, our situation has evolved somewhat. Fret not, friend, we will soon find a new arrangement.}}
				
				{{K|Head! Head!}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				Us hydric hounds are quite the uncommon sight indeed.
				
				{{Y|It is little surprise you have not seen our kind before, friend!}}
				
				{{cloudy|We ask that you greet us separately, for clarity's sake.}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Mutated">
				<text>I am of one mind, but sport several heads myself. I am familiar with people seldom knowing which too adress.</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_RequirePart" Part="TwoHeaded" Render="Mutation: Two-headed" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Relationship">How do you take decisions? Is the matter not uncomfortable?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Start">Duly noted. I had something else to ask you.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live, drink, live, and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="Mutated">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{emote|*The two larger heads look disheartened.*}}

				Count yourself lucky.

				{{Y|Nowadays, silence is worth all the freshwater in Qud, friend.}}

				{{K|Heads!}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{emote|*Both heads nod emphathetically.*}}

				{{cloudy|Folks get confused too easily nowadays.}}
				
				{{Y|I could not imagine sharing the same mind over two heads, friend. That sounds utterly lonely.}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">Can I ask you something else?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink.</choice>		
		</node>

		<node ID="Relationship">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{K|Left! Right! Left! Right!}}
				
				Does that answer your question?
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{Y|Uncomfortable? How so, friend? I get to share every moment with my favorite person in Qud.}}
				
				What Growarow says. Founder knows I could not ask for a better cohead.
				
				{{emote|*The two heads briefly nuzzle each other.*}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">There was something else...</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I will leave you to it then. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="About">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				Up until now, we collected starapples from our herders, and made them sing until jammy.

				{{Y|We used to trade in commodities with the local travelers. We would ask that you excuse our current situation, friend.}}

				{{K|Star! Apples!}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				Will you believe it if we tell you we are a chef? Collecting starapples from our herders, and making them sing until jammy.

				{{Y|We trade in commodities with the local travelers. Does your pack feel too heavy? We have solutions to offer you, friend.}}

				{{cloudy|Whatever you desire, the Growarows are the place to spend freshwater!}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Name">I am confused. Are you called Growarow or Growarows?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Start">This is an impressive pitch. I had something else to ask...</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I will return if I need anything. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="Name">
			<text IfSpeakerEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">			
				{{emote|*The two larger heads exchange a disheartened look.*}}

				The two of us are the Growarows.

				{{Y|As for our new partner, there is no telling what they will want to be called, friend.}}

				{{K|Grarows!}}
			</text>
			<text IfSpeakerNotEvolutiveTileMoreOrEqual="2">
				{{emote|*Both heads exchange a knowing look.*}}

				It is quite simple, really. We are called Growarow.

				{{Y|And we are called Growarow, friend.}}

				{{cloudy|Together, we are the Growarows.}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">I see. My name is =name= -- I wanted to ask you something else.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, Growarows.</choice>	
		</node>
	
</conversation>


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_CatTinker">
		
		<node ID="Start">
			<text IfFinishedQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">
				{{emote|*Imimiw =verb:keep= working without paying much attention to you.*}}
				
				Settle comfortably if you need to, =player.apparentSpecies=, and grab a soldering iron. Work awaits.
			</text>
			<text IfHaveActiveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">
				{{emote|*The tinker's bestacled gaze =verb:gauge= you mercilessly.*}}
				
				There you are, =player.apparentSpecies=! What news from the ripening caves?
			</text>
			<text IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">
				{{emote|*The tinker =verb:turn= towards you, =pronouns.possessive= workshop in complete disarray.*}}
				
				Speak quick, =player.apparentSpecies=! Solder is cooling down already.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Work" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">I am in need of work. Is there any matter I can assist you with?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Shrews" IfHaveActiveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Find" IfNotFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">The vermin in the ripening caves are canyon shrews, tinker. They have been feasting on the village's cheese stocks.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Reward" IfHaveActiveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">I have handled the matter of the vermin in the ripening caves. They will not trouble the village anymore.</choice>
		  	<choice GotoID="Division" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">What is the matter with village behind the wall?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Opinion" IfHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1" IfNotFinishedQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest3" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1~Brief">What do you think of the division between Shik and Spar?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Zanya">You do know someone set up camp in front of your workshop, right?</choice>
  			<choice GotoID="About">What do you do here in Spar?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, feline tinker.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Work">
			<text>
				Yes, yes, I could use a paw or two. I'll speak plainly for you: what do you know about cheese?
				
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:report:afterpronoun= =pronouns.possessive= attention to the electronics sitting disassembled on a nearby countertop, not waiting for your answer.*}}
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Know">
				<text>That is somewhat of a broad question. Are we talking pressed or not? Fresh, cooked or stretched? Soft or mold-ripened? There is also the matter of-</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_RequirePart" Part="CookingAndGathering_Spicer" Render="Cooking and Gathering: Spicer" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="DontKnow">Well, most people would agree it tastes delicious, for starters.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Know">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:cut:afterpronoun= you short, tail whipping the air with impatience.*}}

				Alright, you are an expert, I get it! Founder, no need to brag about the matter. 			
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief">Well, you asked and got your answer. What is the job about?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I don't like your attitude much. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="DontKnow">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:sigh:afterpronoun= audibly, not bothering to turn away from her current work.*}}

				Well, Founder went and delivered a layperson to my door. Provided you can follow simple instructions, you should still be of use. 			
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief1">... That certainly is a choice of words. What do you need to see done?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I don't need to hear more of this -- go find yourself a dairy scholar if you so require one. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Brief1">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The tinker's tone =verb:turn= scholastic with a hint of pride.*}}

				As you may know, much of our output is of porcine dairy. Once pressed, it is left to ripen in special shelves of my doing. You see, those are designed for optimal ventilation and rind blooming...
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief2">{{emote|*listen intently*}}</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Brief2">{{emote|*fidget impatiently*}}</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Brief2">
			<text>
				... You are not paying attention to any of this, are you?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Brief3">I most definitely am, tinker. What would you have me do?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Brief3">Not really. Can we cut to the chase, and get to the part where I am supposed to do something?</choice>
		</node>		
	
		<node ID="Brief3" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:turn:afterpronoun= back to you, letting =pronouns.possessive= chrome work incomplete for the time being.*}}
			
				Well, there has been stealing from the ripening caves. Vermin of some sort, I would wager. I would ask that you go there and solve the matter, any way you see fit. It goes without saying you will be duly compensated for your efforts.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End" IfNotTestState="Brothers_CatsDogs_BeastmasterKilled" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">End the vermin infestation in Spar's cheese ripening caves. Sounds simple enough. Live and drink, tinker -- next time we talk, Spar's food stocks will be safe.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End" IfTestState="Brothers_CatsDogs_BeastmasterKilled" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest" CompleteQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">End the vermin infestation in Spar's cheese ripening caves. Sounds simple enough. Live and drink, tinker -- I have a feeling I have solved the matter already.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Vermin and cheese? This cannot possibly be worth my time. Live and drink, tinker.</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Shrews">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:roll:afterpronoun= eyes behind oscillating eyewear.*}}
			
				So now we know for certain the cheese did not walk away of its own volition. Have you handled the matter of those shrews?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">Not quite yet, but there is another matter we need to discuss.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I am on my way to do just that. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Reward">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Possessive= tail =verb:whip= the air excitedly.*}}
				
				Is the matter truly settled then? Was it... On second thought, do not tell me anything. The less taxing this matter on in my mind, the better.
				
				You have my thanks, =player.apparentSpecies=.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Awkward">It was my pleasure, tinker.</choice>
		</node>		
	
		<node ID="Awkward">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:stay:afterpronoun= silent, reporting =pronouns.possessive= attention on =pronouns.possessive= work.*}}
				
				...				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Awkward2">...</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Awkward2">
			<text>			
				...				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Awkward3">Tinker?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Awkward3">{{emote|*clear throat*}}</choice>
		</node>		
	
		<node ID="Awkward3">
			<text>			
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:jump:afterpronoun=, startled, as parts and bits scatter from the countertops.*}}
				
				Ah! You are still here, =player.apparentSpecies=? Hmm, I wager you must be expecting a reward.				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="GiveMeStuff">This is what you promised.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="GiveMeStuff">I would rather not have battled vermin and get nothing to show for it.</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="GiveMeStuff">
			<text>			
				... Obviously.
				
				{{emote|*The tinker =verb:retrieve= a few items from her well-packed drawers, before handing them to you.*}}
				
				There you go, =player.apparentSpecies=. This would conclude our business, yes? Let it not be said Imimiw ever shorted her associates.				
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End" CompleteQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Debrief" FinishQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">
				<text>I will put those to good use. Live and drink, Imimiw.</text>
				<part Name="ReceiveItem" Blueprints="Brothers_CatsDogs_SparRecoiler,Fixit Spray,Advanced Toolkit" Identify="Brothers_CatsDogs_SparRecoiler" />
			</choice>
		</node>		

		<node ID="Division" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:take:afterpronoun= a sudden bitter interest in a disassembled recoiler.*}} 

				The matter? You'll have to ask our good mayor on that, =player.apparentSpecies=. Or even better, head directly to Warden Arendubark. He is standing guard by the central wall, in the norther outskirts -- you cannot miss him.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">I will ask the warden for more information, then. In the meantime, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>

		<node ID="Opinion">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Possessive= words are laced with frustration, and the fur on =pronouns.possessive= back sticks up slightly.*}}
			
				You know they have a proper merchant in Shik? I am denied a potential supplier, and for what? Some antique reason no living cat remembers? Founder, the whole affair gets on my nerves. Let us talk about something else, =player.apparentSpecies=.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">My apologies, tinker. Let us.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Maybe later -- live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	

		<node ID="Zanya">
			<text>
				Obviously, yes. They help me from time to time -- as it happens, bipedality sometimes proves unexpectantly useful.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">This makes sense. I had another question.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">It does. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	

		<node ID="About">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:knead:afterpronoun= the ground for a few seconds, but =pronouns.possessive= expression quickly shifts to suspicion.*}}
			
				I cut open artifacts, learn of their innards, and put them back together. Somestimes I make more myself, out of the bits and trinkets brought by wandering traders. Are you another student of chrome?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="ATinker">
				<text>I have been known to tinker my own machines when the need arises.</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_RequirePart" Part="Tinkering_Tinker1" Render="Tinkering: Tinker I" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="NotATinker">I dabble. Is that enough to be called a student of chrome?</choice>	
		</node>	

		<node ID="ATinker">
			<text>
				Well, in that case, I hope you can refrain from spouting unsollicited "advice", =player.formalAddressTerm=. If I need pointers, I will ask for them. Now do you need anything else?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">As a matter of fact, I do.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Not right now. Live and drink, tinker.</choice>	
		</node>	

		<node ID="NotATinker">
			<text>
				Founder be thanked! I shall be able to work without "suggestions" on how to do things quicker or more efficiently.
				
				Well, if you need your gear repaired or your trinkets divined, I am the feline to ask.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">Thank you, tinker. There was something else...</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I will keep that in mind. In the meantime, live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	
	
	</conversation>		

	
	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_CatsuitGuy">
			
		<node ID="Start">
			<text IfHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*Zanya =verb:beam= at you.*}}
				
				If it ain't my good friend =name=! Find some shade in our 'uts, meow!
			</text>
			<text IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				Meow, I say. I 'ope you will enjoy our 'umble abodes and fit right 'mong us cats!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Work" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest">Is there work that needs doing?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Division" IfNotHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">What is the matter with the other village?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Opinion" IfHaveQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1" IfNotFinishedQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest3" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1~Brief">What do you think of the current Shik and Spar situation?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="DefinitelyACat" IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">Huh... I "meow" right back at you, fellow cat.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="About">What is there to know about Spar?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I will try to. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Work">
			<text>
				You'll have to check in with the tinker of ours, Imimiw. She's been dealing with some vermin issues lately, meow. She oughta be in her 'orkshop, in that building right o'er there.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">I will see about helping her, thank you. There was something else...</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Duly noted. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Division">
			<text IfHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*Zanya =verb:lean= forward conspiratorially.*}} 

				You noticed too, meow? Lady Morrarri, she's bent on none o' us visiting the other village. Makes for a downright dour atmosphere, le'me tell you.
			</text>
			<text IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:lean:afterpronoun= forward conspiratorially.*}} 

				You noticed too, meow? Lady Morrarri, she's bent on none o' us visiting the other village. Makes for a downright dour atmosphere, le'me tell you.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Who">And that Lady Morrarri would be...?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Fix">Is anyone aiming to solve the matter?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Start">I can imagine. There was something else I wanted to ask.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Thank you for your answer. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Who">
			<text>
				Why, she is Spar's mayor o'course! Although she ain't too keen on the title, prefers to be called a "Lady", meow. Can't blame her, really.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Fix">I see. And did anyone try to speak some sense into her?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Start">There was another matter...</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">I guess not. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="Fix" AllowEscape="false">
			<text IfHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*Zanya =verb:look= left and right before continuing.*}} 
				
				Aye, for sure! Our good 'arden's been looking to solve the matter but he could most definitely use a paw or two, meow. Can't investigate much from 'here he's taken root, see?
			</text>				
			<text IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:look:affterpronoun= left and right before continuing.*}} 
				
				Aye, for sure! Our good 'arden's been looking to solve the matter but he coul' most definitely use a hand or two, meow. Can't investigate much from 'here he's taken root, see? You can find 'im in the northern outskirts.
			</text>			
			<choice GotoID="End" StartQuest="Brothers_CatsDogs_MainQuest1">I will talk to the warden then. In the meantime, live and drink.</choice>
		</node>		
	
		<node ID="Opinion">
			<text IfHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*Zanya =verb:choose= =pronouns.possessive= next words carefully.*}} 

				It all seems a tad excessive to meow. Those dogs from Shik look catlike enough in meow opinion -- not that Lady Morrarri see things the same 'ay.
			</text>
			<text IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:choose:afterpronoun= =pronouns.possessive= next words carefully.*}} 

				It all seems a tad excessive to meow. Those dogs from Shik look catlike enough in meow opinion -- not that Lady Morrarri see things the same 'ay.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Start">I can imagine. There was something else I wanted to ask.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Thank you for your answer. Live and drink.</choice>	
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="DefinitelyACat">
			<text>
				{{emote|*Hope and appreciation light up =pronouns.possessive= face.*}} 
				
				Oh? You do?
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="ACatForReal" SetBooleanState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered,true">
				<text>I do. You're as fine a cat as I've ever seen!</text>
				<part Name="Brothers_ModifyReputation" Faction="Spar" Value="50" Shown="True" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Start">Potentially, but I wanted to ask you something else first.</choice>
		</node>	
		
		<node ID="ACatForReal" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>
				{{emote|*=pronouns.Subjective= =verb:answer:afterpronoun= with excitement palpable through hushed tones, as =pronouns.subjective= =verb:rummage:afterpronoun= through =pronouns.possessive= belongings and produce another headband, similar to the one =pronouns.subjective= =verb:wear:afterpronoun=: triangles of synthetic fibers mounted on a plastifer wreath.*}} 
				
				How good it is to find a similar spir't! You could some of this to look more catlike yourself! I craft those meowself.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Thanks">
				<text>Thank you! I will take good care of this.</text>
				<part Name="ReceiveItem" Blueprints="Brothers_CatsDogs_Catears" Identify="All" />			
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="NoThanks">I am flattered, but feel catlike enough.</choice>
		</node>			
		
		<node ID="Thanks" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>
				{{emote|*They =verb:watch:afterpronoun= intently, expecting you to put the headband on right away.*}} 
				
				Meow name is Zanya, by the way.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Name">Well met, Zanya! I am =name=.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Name">I am not putting it on right away... Nonetheless, you can call me =name=.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="NoThanks" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>
				{{emote|*They =verb:seem:afterpronoun= slightly disappointed, and put the headband back in =pronouns.possessive= pack.*}} 
				
				'Ave it your way, stranger. Meow name is Zanya, by the way.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Name">Well met, Zanya! I am =name=.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Name">I am not putting it on right away... Nonetheless, you can call me =name=.</choice>
		</node>	

		<node ID="Name">
			<text>			
				In that case, 'ave an excellent day, =name=! You know 'here to find meow if you need anything! Live and drink.
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, Zanya.</choice>
		</node>	
	
		<node ID="About">
			<text IfHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*Zanya =verb:tap= =pronouns.possessive= chin pensively.*}} 
				
				Not much to tell about this place, we all keep pretty much t'ourselves. Some o' the others tend to the pig farms, and prepare the cheese. Right o'er there is the 'orkshop of Imimiw, our tinker. She'll set any 'ires straight in just a moment. 
				
				There is the occasional traveler, but otherwise the days are spent working, trading and napping un'er the Hind Sun.							
			</text>				
			<text IfNotHaveState="Brothers_CatsDogs_FurGuyFlattered">
				{{emote|*They =verb:tap:afterpronoun= =pronouns.possessive= chin pensively.*}} 
				
				Not much to tell about this place, we all keep pretty much t'ourselves. Some o' the others tend to the pig farms, and prepare the cheese. Right o'er there is the 'orkshop of Imimiw, our tinker. She'll set any 'ires straight in just a moment. 
				
				There is the occasional traveler, but otherwise the days are spent working, trading and napping un'er the Hind Sun.	
			</text>	
			<choice GotoID="Start">Thank you for the pointers. I have a few questions still.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">That is all I needed to know. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>	
	
	</conversation>	


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_Cheesejaw">
		
		<node ID="Start" IfFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">
			<text>
				eheheheheheh shrooz!~
				geh! me sulton!~
				nyeheheheheh, minemineminemine!~
				sultonofshrooz uhuhuh...~
				liffen. huh. SHROOZ!
			</text>		
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and eat, "sultan".</choice>
		</node>
		
		<node ID="Start" IfNotFinishedQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">
			<text>
				eheheheheheh cheez!~
				geh! me sulton!~
				nyeheheheheh, minemineminemine!~
				sultonofcheez uhuhuh...~
				liffen. huh. CHEEZ!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="What"> 
				<text>Will you resign your charge and swear to unvex the fromagers of this world?</text>
				<part Name="RequireReputation" Faction="Snapjaws" Level="Liked" />
			</choice>		
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink. Milk, preferably.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="What">
			<text>
				unbex? fromfrom? oooh...
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Stop">... Stop stealing the cats' cheese.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">You know what, never mind. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>

		<node ID="Stop">
			<text>
				{{emote|*The snapjaw =verb:stare= at you in disbelief.*}} 
				
				cheez...
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Hungry">They sent me to put a stop to it. So I'm asking you nicely.</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">This is not working. I'll find another way.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Hungry">
			<text>		
				nocheez an me go belly bad... leavendrink!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Solution">
				<text>Wait, is the problem that you'll get hungry without cheese?</text>				
				<part Name="Brothers_RequireStat" Stat="Intelligence" Value="19" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="Byebye">Are you... dismissing me?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, I guess.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Byebye">
			<text>		
				{{emote|*The snapjaw's knuckles go white on =pronouns.possessive= weapon.*}} 
				
				LEAFFENDING!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Fight">
				<text>Well, I did try to resolve things peacefully. Have at you!</text>
				<part Name="StartFight" />
			</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">This will not end well. Live and drink.</choice>
		</node>	

		<node ID="Solution">
			<text>		
				{{emote|*The snapjaw =verb:jump= up and down.*}} 
				
				neheheheheh belly beat me, sulton ov suldon!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="Idea">Could you not simply eat the shrews you've been training?</choice>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, I guess.</choice>
		</node>
	
		<node ID="Idea" AllowEscape="false">
			<text>		
				{{emote|*The snapjaw =verb:lick= =pronouns.possessive= lips, a spark in =pronouns.possessive= gaze.*}} 
				
				uhuhuh smard! crisby juisy tasdy shrooz eheheheh...
				
				gogo! nocheez! suldon eat shroo now! LIBNEAT!
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End" CompleteQuestStep="Brothers_CatsDogs_CheeseQuest~Stop">That seems settled, then. Live and... eat.</choice>
		</node>
	
	
	</conversation>	


<!--Generic NPCs-->


	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_ShikCitizen">
		
		<node ID="Start">
			<text>
				{{emote|*soft growling*}}~
				{{emote|*tired panting*}}~
				Yes? {{emote|*interrogative bark*}}~
				Better not steal them starapples, traveler.~
				{{emote|*starapple in jaws*}} Hon't neeh hanhs to hick sharahhles.~
				Anything I can help ye with? {{emote|*tilting head*}}~
				Take me word for it =player.formalAddressTerm=: always spit out seeds.	
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live, drink, and herd starapples.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>	

	<conversation ID="Brothers_CatsDogs_SparCitizen">
		
		<node ID="Start">
			<text>
				{{emote|*purring*}}~
				{{emote|*soft meowing*}}~
				What now? {{emote|*ears twitching*}}~~
				I en't done with the milking for the day, =player.formalAddressTerm=.~
				Moon and sun, cheese and wafers, =player.formalAddressTerm=.~
				If you en't helping, don't stand in me way.~
				Hmm? {{emote|*licking a paw*}}~
				Get yourself some meat to cook crispy, =player.formalAddressTerm=. You'll thank me later.		  
			</text>
			<choice GotoID="End">Live and drink, pig tender.</choice>
		</node>
	
	</conversation>


</conversations>